Earl Browder Papers
Earl Browder Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - St. Louis Post Dispatch, 1948 (Box 32)
  - Sanders, Gabe, 1949 (Box 32)
  - The Sandpiper Press, 1946; 1947 (Box 32)
  - The Saturday Review, 1946-1948; 1952 (Box 32)
    See Cousins, Norman.
  - [W.B.] Saunders Co., Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1947 (Box 32)
  - Sayre, John Nevin, 1945 (Box 32)
  - Schafer, John Charles, 1939 (Box 32)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr., See Public Affairs Committee, Inc.
  - [Henry] Schuman, Inc., 1947 (Box 32)
  - Schuyler, George Samuel, 1945 (Box 32)
  - Science and Society, 1942; 1947 (Box 32)
  - Science Illustrated, 1947 (Box 32)
  - Science Press, 1949 (Box 32)
  - Scientific American, 1947 (Box 32)
  - Scientific Monthly, 1947 (Box 32)
  - Scott, John, 1962 (Box 32)
  - [William R.] Scott, Inc., 1947 (Box 32)
  - [Charles] Scribner's Sons, 1949 (Box 32)
  - Seattle (Washington) School District, 1948 (Box 32)
  - Seipp, Conrad, 1939 (Box 32)
  - Selford, Jack, 1961-1970; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Sentman, Robert M., 1942 (Box 33)
  - Shanghai Tiffin Club, New York, 1945 (Box 33)
  - Shapiro, Aaron, 1945; 1953 (Box 33)
  - Sheppard, R. Burton, 1937 (Box 33)
  - Sheridan House, Inc., 1946-1949 (Box 33)
  - Sherman, Ray W., 1948 (Box 33)
  - Shoaf, George Henry, 1951; 1953 (Box 33)
  - Shub, Anatole, 1957 (Box 33)
  - Shuster, Zechariah, 1940 (Box 33)
  - Simmonds, H. R., 1944 (Box 33)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1946-1949 (Box 33)
  - Sinarchismo, 1942 (Box 33)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1943 (Box 33)
  - The Slavic American, 1948 (Box 33)
  - [William] Sloane Associates, Inc, 1948 (Box 33)
  - Slochower, Harry, 1945; 1946 (Box 33)
  - Slonim, J., 1940 (Box 33)
  - Slonimsky, Nicholas, 1947 (Box 33)
  - Sluszka, Sigmund J., 1946 (Box 33)
  - Smith, Gerald Lyman Kenneth, 1942; 1943 (Box 33)
  - Smith, Vern Ralph, 1948 (Box 33)
  - Smullin, Isaac M., 1960 (Box 33)
  - Smyth, F. Hastings, 1943 (Box 33)
  - Snow, Sinclair, 1957 (Box 33)
  - Sochen, Freada, 1955 (Box 33)
  - Social Justice, See The Christian Front.
  - "Socialism and Communism in the U.S.A.", See Mindel, Jacob.
  - Socialist Party of Chile, 1942; 1943 (Box 33)
  - Socialist Party of Cuyahoga County (Ohio), 1935 (Box 33)
  - Socialist Party of Indiana, 1946 (Box 33)
  - Socialist Party, USA, 1935-1939 (Box 33)
  - Socialist Workers Party, 1943; 1944 (Box 34)
  - Socoloff, Joseph, 1943 (Box 34)
  - Sokolsky, George Ephraim, 1940-1945 (Box 34)
  - Solis Manufacturers & Importers, Havana, Cuba, 1947 (Box 34)
  - Sorin, Vladimir I., 1931 (Box 34)
  - Soong Ching-ling, 1942; 1943 (Box 34)
  - South America, 1943 (Box 34)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare, 1958 (Box 34)
  - Soviet Purchasing Commission, 1946 (Box 34)
  - Soviet Russia Today, 1947-1949 (Box 34)
  - Spachner, Leopold, 1946 (Box 34)
  - Spadea syndicate, 1953 (Box 34)
  - Spanish Nazi organizations in Mexico, 1941 (Box 34)
  - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign, 1939 (Box 34)
  - Sparks, Nemmy, 1941 (Box 34)
  - Spectorsky, Auguste C., See Twentieth Century Fox Films Corporation.
  - Speiser, Maurice J. and Herbert A., 1947 (Box 34)
  - Spivak, Lawrence, See Meet the Press.
  - Springfield (Massachusetts) Sunday Union and Republican, 1943 (Box 34)
  - Stachel, Jacob "Jack" (Box 34)
  - Stalin, Joseph, 1941; incoming only (Box 34)
  - Standard Oil Corporation, 1940 (Box 34)
  - Starobin, Joseph R., 1956-1959 (Box 34)
  - State Department Employee Loyalty Investigation, 1950 (Box 34)
  - Stechert-Hafner, Inc, 1948 (Box 34)
  - Stedman, Seymour, 1917; 1943 (Box 34)
  - Stenographers, Typewriters, Bookkeepers and Assistants Union of Kansas City, 1915 (Box 34)
  - Stern, Carl S., 1943 (Box 34)
  - Stettinius, Edward, Jr, 1944 (Box 34)
  - Stone, Allen, 1963 (Box 34)
  - Stone, Isidor Feinstein, 1954-1957 (Box 34)
  - Strachey, Celia, undated (Box 34)
  - Strachey, John, 1957 (Box 34)
  - Strecker, Joseph George, 1938 (Box 34)
  - Strobell, Caroline Lloyd, 1939 (Box 34)
  - Strong, Anna Louise, 1925; 1943,; 1951-1953 (Box 34)
  - Strother, Shelby F., 1939 (Box 34)
  - Struik, Dirk Jan, 1942; 1945,; 1946 (Box 34)
  - Stryker, George P., 1956-1958 (Box 34)
  - Sullivan, Edward Francis, 1938 (Box 34)
  - Summit Press, Publishers, 1946 (Box 34)
  - Superior School of Commerce, Quebec, 1948 (Box 34)
  - Survey, 1964 (Box 34)
  - Survey Associates, Inc., 1947 (Box 34)
  - Swing, Raymond Gram, 1943 (Box 34)
  - Sylvis, William H., undated (Box 34)
  - Syracuse University Library, 1970 (Box 34)
  - T, 1937-1962 (Box 35)
  - Taft, Clinton J., See American Civil Liberties Union.
  - Tallentyre, Molly, undated (Box 35)
  - Tarasov-Rodinov, Aleksandr, 1932 (Box 35)
  - Telford, Shirley, 1960 (Box 35)
  - The Tennessee Group (Marxist), 1946 (Box 35)
  - Tested Toy Laboratory, 1946 (Box 35)
  - Thackery, Ted O., See The Daily Compass.
  - Theatre Arts, 1947 (Box 35)
  - This Week Magazine, 1947 (Box 35)
  - Thomas, Ben, 1940 (Box 35)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1934-1939; 1950,; 1951,; 1953,; 1957,; 1963 (Box 35)
  - [Charles C.] Thomas, Publisher, 1947 (Box 35)
  - Time, 1948; 1951 (Box 35)
  - Tito, Josip Broz, 1947 (Box 35)
  - Toohey, Patrick, 1941; 1943,; 1945 (Box 35)
  - Totten, Edward P., 1948 (Box 35)
  - Town Hall, Inc., 1939; 1943-1947 (Box 35)
  - Trachtenberg, Alexander, 1936; 1942 (Box 35)
  - Trade Union Educational League, 1923-1927 (Box 35)
  - Trade Union Unity League, 1930 (Box 35)
  - Trade unions, post World War II, 1947-1949 (Box 35)
  - Translators (Russian-English), 1946; 1947 (Box 35)
  - Transport Workers' Union of America, 1948-1950; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Travel, 1947 (Box 35)
  - Tresca, Carlo, 1943 (Box 36)
  - Trimble, South, 1940 (Box 36)
  - Trotskyites (militant), 1939; 1940 (Box 36)
  - Trud (Труд), 1937; 1938 (Box 36)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1945; incoming only (Box 36)
  - Turner, Nina Winona Browder (Box 36)
  - Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation, 1946 (Box 36)
  - U.S. Camera, 1947 (Box 36)
  - U.S. Committee Against Militarization, undated (Box 36)
  - Ukrainians in America, 1953; undated (Box 36)
  - Unemployment Insurance Act, 1930 (Box 36)
  - Unger, Abraham, 1942 (Box 36)
  - Union Democratica Boliviana, See Communist Party, Bolivia.
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics Consulate New York, NY, 1948 (Box 36)
  - United Asia Magazine, 1949 (Box 36)
  - United Auto Workers, 1944 (Box 36)
  - United Automobile Workers of America (Box 36)
  - United Christian Council for Democracy, 1944 (Box 36)
  - United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America, 1945 (Box 36)
  - United Labor Council of America, 1923 (Box 36)
  - United Labor May Day Committee, 1936 (Box 36)
  - United Mine Workers of America, 1943 (Box 36)
  - United Nations World, 1947 (Box 36)
  - United Office and Professional Workers of America, 1944-1946 (Box 36)
  - United Polish Workers Party, See Communist Party, Poland.
  - United Spanish Women Committee, 1940 (Box 36)
  - United State Publishing (OGIZ), Soviet Union, 1947 (Box 36)
  - United States Army, 1942; 1943 (Box 36)
  - United States Army Medical Library, 1946 (Box 36)
  - United States Army Procurement and Accounting Division, 1948 (Box 36)
  - United States Civil Service Commission, 1944 (Box 36)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1930; 1942,; 1943 (Box 36)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, Section on Agronomy, 1948 (Box 36)
  - United States Department of Justice, 1939; 1943,; 1949 (Box 36)
  - United States Department of Justice Foreign Agent Registration, 1946-1949 (Box 36)
  - United States Department of State, 1939; 1947,; 1949 (Box 36)
    See also Welles, Benjamin Sumner.
  - United States Department of State, Division of Controls, 1939 (Box 36)
  - United States Department of State, Division of Northern European Affairs, 1944 (Box 36)
  - United State Department of State, Passport Office, 1958 (Box 36)
  - United States Federal Security Agency, 1942 (Box 37)
  - United States Information Agency, 1957 (Box 37)
  - United States Government Printing Office, Superintendent of Documents, 1947 (Box 37)
  - United States House of Representatives, Congressional Committee for the Protection of Consumers, 1943 (Box 37)
  - United States House of Representatives, Special Committee on Un-American Activities, 1939 (Box 37)
  - United States House of Representatives, Special Committee on Campaign Expenditures, 1944 (Box 37)
  - United States Library of Congress, 1946; 1948 (Box 37)
  - United States Library of Congress, Copyright Office, 1945-1948 (Box 37)
  - The United States News, 1939 (Box 37)
  - United States Office of War Information, 1942 (Box 37)
  - United States Office of War Mobilization, 1942 (Box 37)
  - United States Penitentiary, Atlanta, Georgia, 1941 (Box 37)
  - United Staes Penitentiary, Leavenworth, Kansas, 1936 (Box 37)
  - United States Post Office Department, 1944; 1947 (Box 37)
  - United States Reconstruction Finance Corporation, 1943 (Box 37)
  - United States relations with the Soviet Union, 1941; 1942 (Box 37)
  - United States Selective Service System, 1940 (Box 38)
  - United States Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, Subcommittee Investigating the State Department, 1950 (Box 38)
  - United States Senate Committee on Government Operations, 1953 (Box 38)
  - United States Senate Committee on the Judiciary, 1955 (Box 38)
  - United States Treasury Department, Bureau of Customs, 1948 (Box 38)
  - United States v. Earl Browder 2 USC 192 (1951)
    - "Contempt of Congress: The Trial of Earl Browder", 1951 (Box 38)
    - Indictment, 1950 (Box 38)
    - Lawyers' notes, 1951 (Box 38)
    - Motion for directed verdict, 1951 (Box 38)
    - Motion to dismiss, 1951 (Box 38)
    - Publicity, 1951 (Box 38)
    - Transcripts, 1951 (Box 38)
  - United States v. Earl Browder 22 USC 220 (1940)
    - Appeal, 1940 (Box 39)
    - Clemency, 1942 (Box 39)
    - Lawyers' notes and correspondence, 1940 (Box 39)
    - Prison release congratulations
      - A-Z, 1942; 4 folders (Box 39)
      - Unsigned, 1942 (Box 40)
      - Communist Party branches, 1942 (Box 40)
      - Organizations, 1942 (Box 40)
      - Unions, 1942 (Box 40)
  - United States v. Earl Russell Browder, etc, 1940 (Box 41)
  - United States v. Irene Raissa Browder and Earl Browder, 1952-1954; 2 folders (Box 41)
  - United States v. Raissa Berkmann Browder
    - Briefs, memoranda, supporting documents, 1940-1943 (Box 41)
    - Clippings, 1943; 1944 (Box 41)
    - Drafts of letters, memos, reports, 1943; 1944 (Box 41)
    - Letters, unfavorable, 1943; 1944 (Box 41)
    - Letters of support
      - Church groups, 1943; 1944 (Box 41)
      - Individuals, 1943; 1944 (Box 41)
      - Organizations, 1943; 1944 (Box 41)
      - Unions, 1943; 1944 (Box 42)
      - Women, 1943; 1944 (Box 42)
    - Transcripts, 1943; 1944 (Box 42)
  - United States vs. Michael Obermeier 8 USC 746 (1948), 1950 (Box 42)
  - United States v. Welwel Waszower 312 USC 342 (1941), 1940 (Box 42)
  - United States War Labor Administration, 1936 (Box 42)
  - United States War Manpower Commission, 1942 (Box 42)
  - United States War Production Board, 1942; 1943 (Box 42)
  - United States Works Progress Administration, Adult Education Program, 1937 (Box 42)
  - United War Veterans, 1939 (Box 42)
  - Universal Oil Products Company, 1946 (Box 42)
  - University Book Store, Seattle, Washington, 1948 (Box 42)
  - University Books, Inc., 1960 (Box 42)
  - University of California General Library, 1948 (Box 42)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1946; 1957,; 1958,; 1970 (Box 42)
  - University of Miami, 1947 (Box 42)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1947 (Box 42)
  - University of Southern California, 1948 (Box 42)
  - University of Virginia Alderman Library, 1948 (Box 42)
  - University of Virginia Institute of Public Affairs, 1939 (Box 42)
  - University of Washington Far Eastern Institute, 1948 (Box 42)
  - University Place Book Shop New York, NY, 1948 (Box 42)
  - V, 1938-1948 (Box 43)
  - [D] Van Nostrand Co. Inc., 1947 (Box 43)
  - Vanguard Press, 1935; 1946 (Box 43)
  - Varga, Eugen Samuilovich, "Changes in the Economics of Capitalism as a Result of the Second World War", 1946; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Vanguard Press, 1935; 1946 (Box 43)
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars, Lt. Quentin Roosevelt Post, undated (Box 43)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Inc., 1940; 1942,; 1944 (Box 43)
  - View, The Modern Magazine, 1947 (Box 43)
  - The Viking Press, Inc., 1946; 1947,; 1957 (Box 43)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1945 (Box 43)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, 1947 (Box 43)
  - Vogue, 1947 (Box 43)
  - Volksfront, 1938 (Box 43)
  - W, 1940-1957 (Box 43)
  - Wahr's Bookstores, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1948 (Box 43)
  - Waldron, Francis X., See Dennis, Eugene. (Box 43)
  - Wallace, Henry A., 1942; 1946,; 1947 (Box 43)
  - [John] Wanamaker, Inc, 1948 (Box 43)
  - War Congress of American Industry, See National Association of Manufacturers.
  - War workers training, 1944; 1947,; 1948,; 1954 (Box 43)
  - Ward, Harry Frederick (Box 43)
    See also American Civil Liberties Union.
  - Warszower, Welwel, See United States vs. Welwel Warszomer.
  - Watkins, Arthur Vivian, 1948 (Box 43)
  - Wayne University, 1960 (Box 43)
  - WBAI-FM, New York, NY, 1960 (Box 43)
  - WBZ-TV, Boston, MA (Box 43)
  - Weems, Charles, 1941; 1942 (Box 44)
  - Weickers, Richard, 1939; 1940 (Box 44)
  - Weinstone, William Wolf, 1942; 1943 (Box 44)
  - Welles, Benjamin Sumner, 1948 (Box 44)
    See also United States Department of State.
  - Wellesley College Library, 1946 (Box 44)
  - West, W. Benjamin, 1948 (Box 44)
  - Western Reserve University, 1946; 1947 (Box 44)
  - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1962; 1963 (Box 44)
  - Weston, Shirley Telford, 1948 (Box 44)
  - "What's On Your Mind?" WQXR Radio, 1942 (Box 44)
  - Wheeldin, Herbert L., 1953 (Box 44)
  - White, Harry Dexter, 1946 (Box 44)
  - Whitman, Willson W., 1947 (Box 44)
  - Whittlesey House Publishing, 1946 (Box 44)
  - WHN, New York, NY, 1920 (Box 44)
  - Wicks, Herbert "Harry" M. (Box 44)
  - Widen, Luther Emanuel, See Ney, Lew (pseudonym).
  - Wilcox & Follett Co., 1943 (Box 44)
  - Wilder, Isabel, 1947; 1948 (Box 44)
  - [John] Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1948 (Box 44)
  - Williams, Vassily Robertovich, 1947 (Box 44)
  - The Williams & Wilkins Company, 1946 (Box 44)
  - Williams College, Williamstown, Massachusetts, 1930-1945 (Box 44)
  - Williamson, John, 1942; 1944 (Box 44)
  - Willkie, Wendell, 1935 (Box 44)
  - Wills, Charles F., 1953 (Box 44)
  - Wilson, Earl, 1947 (Box 44)
  - [The H.H.] Wilson Company, 1944 (Box 44)
  - Winchell, Walter, 1944 (Box 44)
  - Winter, Carl, 1935 (Box 44)
  - Wisconsin Farmer-Labor Progressive Federation, 1963 (Box 44)
  - WNBC, New York, NY, 1945 (Box 44)
  - Wolfe, Bertram David, 1947 (Box 44)
  - Woman's Home Companion, 1940 (Box 44)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1946; 1947 (Box 44)
  - WOR Radio, New York, NY, 1936 (Box 44)
  - Workers Alliance of America, 1953 (Box 44)
  - Workers Defense League, 1939 (Box 44)
  - Workers Education Bureau of America, 1924 (Box 44)
  - Workers' International Relief, 1943; 1950 (Box 44)
  - Workers Library Publishers (Box 44)
  - Workers Party of America (Box 45)
  - Workers School, New York, NY, See Weinstone, William Wolf.
  - Workers School, Youngstown, Ohio, undated (Box 45)
  - The Workers' World (Box 45)
  - The World Community, See Alexander, Gross Wilbur.
  - World Congress of Women, 1943 (Box 45)
  - World Jewish Congress, 1930 (Box 45)
  - World News Service, 1943 (Box 45)
  - World Peaceways, Inc, 1947 (Box 45)
  - World Report, 1946; 1948 (Box 45)
  - [A.A.] Wyn, Inc., 1945 (Box 45)
  - Y, 1948 (Box 45)
  - Yale Co-operative Corporation, 1943 (Box 45)
  - Yale Political Union, 1946-1950 (Box 45)
  - Yale University Press, 1942; 1943 (Box 45)
  - Yergan, Max, 1946 (Box 45)
  - Yonkers Club, 1943 (Box 45)
  - Young, Art, 1939 (Box 45)
  - Young, Max, 1947 (Box 45)
  - Young, Robert R., 1923; 1930,; 1934,; 1939,; 1940 (Box 45)
  - Young Communist League, 1943 (Box 45)
  - Young Communist League, Sweden, 1940 (Box 45)
  - Young Peoples Socialist League, 1947 (Box 45)
  - Young Scott Books, 1955 (Box 45)
  - Yugoslav Information Center, 1943 (Box 45)
  - Yugoslav Partisans, 1941 (Box 45)
  - Yugoslavia, 1946; 1948 (Box 45)
  - Z, undated (Box 45)
  - Zack, Joseph, 1951 (Box 45)
  - Zagreb Peace Conference, 1929 (Box 45)
  - Zam, Herbert, 1963 (Box 45)
  - Zaretsky, Eli S., 1963 (Box 45)
  - Zeligs, Meyer A., 1947 (Box 45)
  - Zhdanov, Andrei Alexandrovich, undated (Box 45)
  - Zhou Enlai, 1946-1948 (Box 45)
  - Ziff-Davis Publishing Company, 1944 (Box 45)
  - [Ted] Zittel, Inc., undated (Box 45)
  - Unidentified and fragments (Box 45)
  - Unidentified and unfriendly (Box 45)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - 1919 (Box 46)
      Excerpts from writings, 1919
    - 1925 (Box 46)
      On the Question of Party Reorganization, 1925
    - 1928 (Box 46)
      The Imperialist Dilemma in China, The China Outlook, 4/1/1928
    - 1929 (Box 46)
      Preparing the Indian Revolution, The Communist, 4/1929
    - 1930 (Box 46)
      Down with the War Makers!, circa 1930
      Economic Crisis and the Third Period, circa 1930
    - 1932 (Box 46)
      United Workers Cooperative Association expulsions, Revolutionary Age, circa 1932
    - 1936 (Box 46)
      EPIC movement and Upton Sinclair, 1936
      A Farmer-Labor Party This Year, 1936
      The Communist Party and Civil Liberties in the United States, circa 1936
      Do Americans Want Communism?, circa 1936
      Interview, Mr. Lopez, 1936
      Draft Election Platform, CPUSA, 1936
    - 1936 Feb-Nov (Box 46)
      Abe Lincoln: Champion of the People, Sunday Worker, 2/16/1936
      text of speech on CBS Radio, Daily Worker, 3/6/1936
      The Farmer-Labor Party -- The People's Front in the U.S.A., Communist International, 5/1936
      The Presidential Elections in The United States, Communist International, 11/13/1936
      Are We Going Communist?, Forum and Century, 11/1936
    - 1937 (Box 46)
      Draft Resolution on the Struggle for Peace, CPUSA, circa 1937
      The Naval Bill and a Peace Program, circa 1937
      The Constitutional Crisis in the United States, 1937
      The Jewish People in the Soviet Union, 1937
      Neutrality, 1937
      About the Crisis in Zionism, 1937
    - 1937 May-Nov (Box 46)
      Letter to the editor, The New Republic, 5/17/1937
      Revolutionary Background of the U.S. Constitution, 8/9/1937
      Letter to the editor, Associated Press, 10/18/1937
      Mobilize the People to Realize the President's Peace Program, Report (CPUSA?), 10/1937
      Letter to the editor, Moscow Redakcia Trud, 11/17/1937
      Twenty Years of Soviet Power, 11/1937
    - 1937-1938 (Box 46)
      Concerted Action or Isolation as the Path to Peace (two versions), radio speech published in New Masses, 1937 or 1938
    - 1938 (Box 46)
      Remarks upon the book: "Conquest of the Past" by Prince von Loewenstein, 1938
      A Long-Term Policy in the Fight For Peace, circa 1938
      An Historic report on the South, 1938
      Twenty One Years Of Struggle For Peace, The Communist, 1938
      The United States and the New International Situation, 1938
    - 1938 Feb-Dec (Box 46)
      A Letter to the Madison Square Garden Meeting, 2/21/1938
      Some Lessons of the Moscow Trials, 3/1938
      Questions and answers, Orchestra Hall, Chicago, 4/6/1938
      Press release on Max Eastman libel suit, 5/12/1938
      The Democratic Front: For Jobs, Security, Democracy and Peace, Report to the Tenth National Convention CPUSA, 5/28/1938
      Tenth National Convention Of The C.P.U.S.A., Pravda, 5/1938
      Results fot the U.S.A. from the Munich Pact and the Betrayal of Democracy and Peace, memorandum, 10/13/1938
      Letter to the editor, Communist International, 10/24/1938
      Letter to the editor, Communist International, 11/1/1938
      Lessons of the 1938 Elections, 11/1938
      C.I. Manifesto, 11/21/1938
      Concerning American Revolutionary Traditions, The Communist, 12/1938
    - 1939 (Box 46)
      Invasion of Poland, 1939
      Appeal to Reason, 1939
      Questions re:CPUSA, 1939
      America and the Communist International, 1939
      How To Tell an Anti-Democrat and How To Beat Him, Bulletin of the National Association of Secondary-School Principals, 1939
      May Day in America, Pravda, 1939
      On Stalin's Sixtieth Birthday, The Communist, 1939
      Your Generation And Mine, 1939
    - 1939 Jan-Dec (Box 46)
      Mastery of Theory and Methods of Work, The Communist, 1/1939
      Letter to the editor, Catholic Chronicle, 1/11/1939
      Lenin and His influence in America, Pravda, 1/12/1939
      Full Text of Browder's Address at Boston, 3/6/1939
      Soviet Economy in the World Today, New Masses, 3/21/1939
      Earl Browder Answers Questions, New Masses, 3/28/1939
      Letter to the editor, New Masses, 4/10/1939
      Text of browder's Reply to Comrade Avarez, The Worker[?], 4/23/1939
      Text of speech at Kings County Communist Councilmanic election campaign, The Worker, 4/27/1939
      Text of speech at Ninth YCL Convention, The Worker, 5/14/1939
      Perspectives on the 1940 Presidential Election, The Communist, 6/1939
      The significance of the Soviet-German Non-Agression Pact, 8/30/1939
      The Role of the Party, The Worker[?], 9/3/1939
      Press release - America and the Imperialist War, 9/15/1939
      Some Remarks On The Twentieth Anniversary Of The C.P.U.S.A, The Communist, 9/1939
      Summary remarks of Plenum, The Communist, 9/1939
      The Communists and the War, 11/29/1939
      Stalin's Sixtieth Birthday, The Communist, 12/29/1939
      Remarks at the funeral of M.J. Olgin, The Communist, 12/1939
    - 1940 (Box 47)
      Some Inner Contradictions In Washington's Imperialist Foreign Policy, circa 1940
      Summary of memorandum "Britain's War Economy at the Opening of the Second Year of the Conflict", 1940
      Draft Election Platform, CPUSA, 1940
      Can Democracy Put Men Back to Work?, Current History, 1940
      Comments on the endorsement of Wendell Willkie by John L. Lewis, 1940
    - 1940 Jan-Dec (Box 47)
      Acceptance message CPUSA nomination for 14th (NY) Congressional Campaign, The Worker[?], 1/6/1940
      UMW provocation, 1/27/1940
      Speech to the Jury, The Communist, 1/22/1940
      Campaign address, 14th (NY) Congressional District, unknown, 1/28/1940
      Campaign address, 14th (NY) Congressional District, unknown, 2/1/1940
      Campaign address, 14th (NY) Congressional District, unknown, 2/6/1940
      Election results in the 14th (NY) Congressional District, unknown, 2/7/1940
      Carrying High the Banner, unknown, 2/11/1940
      Letter to the editor, The Nation, 2/28/1940
      To the People Will Belong the Victory, The Communist, 2/1940
      Peace in Finland: A Decisive Setback For The Incendiaries Of A New World War, The Communist, 4/1940
      May Day in the United States, Pravda, 5/1/1940
      Imperialist War, Report to the Eleventh National Convention CPUSA, 5/30/1940
      On Some Aspects of Foreign Policy, 10/1940
      America and the War Situation, University of Chicago Pulse, 12/30/1940
    - 1941 (Box 47)
      Letter to the editor, New York Times, circa 1941
      Now Is The Time To Fight, 1941
      The Spirit Of America And FDR's Inaugural Address, New Masses, 1/28/1941
      Washington Finances Chinese Civil War, 2/1941
    - 1942 (Box 47)
      Nikifor Grigorieff, memorandum, circa 1942
      Article for London re: Second Front, 1942
    - 1942 Jun-Dec (Box 47)
      Campaign address, 14th (NY) Congressional District, 1/28/42
      On The Anniversary of the Patriotic War..., Intercontinent News, 6/5/1942
      Wallace And Welles Speeches Point Toward People's War Policies Needed For Victory, The Worker, 6/5/1942
      The Speeches of Wallace and Welles, The Worker, 6/7/1942
      Finland, 6/10/1942